All right, time to set up our virtual environment.
Now, there are a lot of things that we must do first, as we said, we must create a virtual machine
that we are going to use for that.
We need the virtualization software and the operating system that we want to install.
The operating system that we're going to use will be clinics, as we previously mentioned.
And also besides that, we will also need our virtual machine that will host vulnerable Web pages that
we can attack.
And another way that we're going to practice will be through a website called Tri Hack Me.
Now, this website does offer a paid subscription, but we're going to cover things that the website
offers for free just so we can include everyone inside of it.
It has really good practice examples of website vulnerabilities with the combination of vulnerable virtual
machine and with practice.
Examples on this website will cover most known and most common website vulnerabilities.
OK, let's first start off by downloading Virtual Box, which is the virtualization software that we
use, and let's also download our clinic's operating system.
Let's start with virtual box first to download Virtual Box.
We want to navigate to the page virtual box dot org.
It will lead you to this official page of the website, and if you want, you can read through all of
these articles and about four toybox if you'd like.
But right now, we're going to see how we can download and install it.
As it says, it has a big download button.
Just click on it and it will lead us to this page, which will offer us different platform packages
based on which operating system you're running.
As we can see, the current version is six point one point eighteen.
And the current platform packages that they have are for Windows hosts or OSX hosts, Linux distributions
and Solaris hosts.
Depending on your operating system, you want to choose which one you want to install.
Since I'm running windows on this machine, I will click on Windows Host.
It will ask me what it wants to download a virtual box just like desktop and click save.
And as you can see, it will start downloading it right here.
Since I already have it, I will just cancel this download, already have it installed.
So I'm not going to do that right now.
And while it's downloading for you, let's navigate to the clinic's official website, which is Etling
Kelly dot org, and let's see how we can download Cal Linux operating system.
OK, so we open up this page, it is the most advanced penetration testing distribution.
And as with Purtle Box, it has this download button.
Let's click on it.
And it will lead us to the official download page now this download page offers the newest release of
Linux or should I say the newest official release, because you also have the weekly unstable and untested
releases.
We're interested in the official stable release.
Currently, it is the clinic's two thousand twenty one point one and the new version of clinics actually
comes out pretty much every two months.
So if you encounter a new version of Linux or a newer version of your toolbox, feel free to download
that one instead, since right now the newest one is two thousand twenty one point one.
I will download this.
Now, we have quite a few options right here that we can choose from.
We have the 64 bit in-store clinics, 64 bit live and clinics, 64 bit net insular as well.
We have four Apple and one we have clinics are 60 for installer.
We have the live and the net installer.
And we also have four 32 bit systems.
Now, if you're running Apple and one, you can go with this one.
If you're running a 64 bit machine, you can go with Kalanak, 64 bit insular.
And if you're in any case, which I doubt anyone will be running at 32 bit machine.
But if you do, you can download clinics, 32 bit insular.
Now, since I'm running a 64 bit Windows machine, I will go with Kalinich 64 bit insular if I click
on this.
It will once again ask me where I want to download it.
I will select desktop and I will click save.
You will notice that the size of this file is pretty large.
It's four gigabytes, so it will take some time.
Now, luckily, I already have it, so I'm just going to cancel this download.
You just wait for both of your downloads to finish and then we can proceed.
Oh, and by the way, you also have an option to download it over Torrent if you'd like.
It's completely up to you.
OK, awesome.
Now, let's say that you have both of your files ready if you don't just post this video until your
downloads are finished and you should have these two files on your desktop.
Let's go with installing a virtual box first.
So to do that, we can double click the installer file.
It will open the welcome window we want to just go next to we want to go next here as well and here
you can check some option if you don't like, we'll just create the shortcut on the desktop.
And I will leave everything checked and click on next.
And here we have a warning that says installing the Oracle virtual box networking feature will reset
your network connection and temporarily disconnect you from the network.
Proceed with the installation now.
So this pretty much says, in case you're doing something important over the Internet, make sure you
finish with that first before installing virtual box.
Otherwise, you might have some Internet connection problems during the installation.
I will just select here, proceed and I will click install.
OK, so here it asks for administrator password.
Since I don't have one, I will just click here.
Yes.
And it will install a virtual box for me.
This doesn't take much time.
It takes maybe a minute or two depending on your system and once it finishes it should open up your
virtual box.
And here is the finished window.
We want to check StarTalk for Tool Box and click on Finish.
Let's wait a couple of seconds, and here it is.
This is the window of Oracle for Tool Box.
Now, let's do one more thing before we end this video.
Let's see how we can create a virtual machine inside the virtual box.
So this is the official window that we have.
We have a couple of buttons right here.
And here will be our machines that we currently don't have.
So let's create one.
Let's create our colonics virtual machine.
To do that, we want to click on this button that says you click on it and it will ask us for a couple
of information, name of the virtual machine.
And here, let's say that we type Kaldi two thousand twenty one.
Here you can select the path where the machine folder will be stored, here we select the type of operating
system and since Cal Linux is a Linux operating system, we will select right here, Linux.
And the version now this can be a little bit tricky if you don't know, but luckily I'm here to tell
you that Carol Lin is based on Debian, so we want to select here Debian 64 bit, or in case you have
a 32 bit machine, you want to select Debian 32 a bit.
Since we downloaded the clinic 64 bit and we have a 64 bit machine, we want to proceed with the version
of Debian 64 bit.
Let's click on Next.
The next thing that it asks us is what ram memory we want to give to this virtual machine.
This is completely up to you.
I'm just here to advise you that you should not go below one gigabyte ram and two gigabyte of RAM is
pretty much all you need.
You don't need more than this.
If you have like four gigabyte ram or less, feel free to proceed by setting only one gigabyte.
But since I have more than four gigabytes of RAM on my house machine, I can set here at least two gigabytes.
If you have like thirty two gigabytes of RAM on your machine, you can even increase this up to four
or eight gigabytes of RAM depending on how fast you want your machine to work.
Now I'm completely fine with two, so I'm just going to select two thousand forty eight megabytes and
I'm going to click on Next under the hard disk.
It asks us for a couple of options.
We just want to stick with the one that's already checked, which is create a virtual hard disk now
and we want to click on create the hard disk file type will be VDI or virtual box disk image.
Click on next.
And storage on a physical hard disk.
This is completely up to you.
I'm just going to go with the NEMATI allocated and you have the explanation of both of these right here.
As it says, a dynamically allocated hard disk file will only use based on your physical hard disk as
it fills up up to the maximum fixed site, although it will not shrink again automatically.
One space on it is frit and a fixed size hard disk file may take longer to create that subsystems,
but it is often faster to use.
So a fixed size is indeed sometimes faster to use, but nonetheless, I'm just going to go with dynamically
allocated and I'm going to click on next.
And the last option, I believe, is how much this size we want to give to our virtual machine.
Now, I advise you not to go below 25 to 30 gigabytes of hard disk space.
I'm just going to select here like thirty eight.
It doesn't really matter.
You can give it more or less if you'd like, but don't go below twenty to twenty five gigabytes.
Otherwise your machine might not work.
OK, now that we selected all of this we can click on create and as you can see we created our first
virtual machine.
We have it right here as well as we have it's information on the right.
We have its general information system, information display settings, storage settings and a bunch
of other things that we are going to take a look at in the next video.
This doesn't mean that our machine will work.
We still have an operating system to install before being able to use this machine.
For now, we only created it inside a virtual box.
In the next video, we're going to add our Linux operating system or ISO image that we downloaded from
the official website.
And we are going to install it inside of this virtual machine.
And hopefully by the end of next video, we will have a working clinics virtual machine.