Welcome back.
Just a quick update on the new Kalvin website.
OK, so they have just changed the downloads section of this page and how they made it can be a little
bit confusing.
So I'm just making a quick update video to explain which exact version should you download.
So once you navigate to the calendar page, navigate to the download section and this is the new design,
they separated different versions into different categories on this page.
Now, since we talked about virtual machines, it might seem to you that we want to go to the virtual
machines and download a version from here, but not exactly for our course.
We want to go to the bare metal.
Click on that.
And here we want to download the version accordingly, we select 60 Forbert or 32 bit depending on our
machine.
Since my machine is 64 bit, I would go with the 64 bit version.
If you're running an apple and one chip, then you want to select this one.
Since once again, I'm running sixty four bit, I want to go sixty four bit insular and it will download
the ISO image on my desktop.
Awesome.
That's all that they wanted to say.
And let's continue with the course.