Welcome back.
So in the previous video, we created our first virtual machine inside the bubble virtual box.
Now it is time that we install our clinics operating system inside of this machine.
But to be able to do that, we want to change some settings inside of this machine first before we actually
started.
So to access the settings of a virtual machine, we can select the virtual machine inside of our virtual
box manager and click on settings.
Now, to even be able to install the clinic's operating system, we must first add it to this machine,
right?
And to do that inside a virtual box, we must navigate to the storage settings and under the controller
idea.
We want to click on this ad icon.
And if you didn't see it really well, it just looks like a disk with a plus pretty much click on it
and you want to click on this ad button right here.
Once you do that, you want to navigate to wherever you have your ISO image saved or your Linux image
saved, for me it's on desktop and you want to double click it.
Then you want to select it right here in this small window and you want to click on CHOOSE.
Now, under the control idea, you will have your clinic's image and you will have this empty image.
Now, this empty image we don't really need.
So we can just.
Right.
Click it and remove attachment and we will be left with just called in two thousand twenty one point
one version.
OK, another thing that we want to do inside of the settings is we want to navigate to the network settings
and we want to change the net to Bridgid adapter.
Now, if you want to read more about these adapters inside the virtual box, you can check out our networking
PDF file that we created for this course.
And it has an explanation on all of these adapters right here and why we use this one.
In short words, we use the adapter because it allows our DCPI from our network to give an IP address
to our clinics virtual machine.
And in this case, our clinic's virtual machine will be viewed as another device on our network.
It will be able to communicate with all the other devices inside of our network, with our router,
with a laptop that you might have connected with your mobile device.
But if you have it under net, which is by default, it won't be able to do it.
So let's just change it to breach the adapter.
And under here, you want to select the adapter name or the adapter that you want to use.
Now, what I found from personal experience is that if you go with the cable connection, it most likely
will always work now via wireless adapters, not to create problems sometimes, and they might need
some additional TRIVERS installation in order to run.
So if you're able to try going with cable or wired connection, OK, these are the two settings that
we wanted to change.
Once we do that, we can click on OK, and right now we are ready to start our virtual machine.
To do that, we want to click on this start erro.
And it will run our virtual machine or it will start the installation process of Linux.
Remember, it's an operating system, so it must be installed first.
Here is the window of our rental machine, and you will notice if you try to enlarge it, it will pretty
much stay the same size.
It will have this white surrounding it.
But don't worry, it will not stay like this forever.
It will only stay like this during the installation.
So what we want to do is we want to choose the graphical install right here in this menu.
You can also go with install about the graphical install.
Looks a little bit better.
Let's click here.
Enter.
And by the way, your mouth will not work inside of the virtual machine yet during the installation.
So you must navigate with your keyboard inside of the installation process.
Let's wait for the next step.
And here it is, we want to select the language to be English for me, you can choose whichever language
you want the location.
It doesn't really matter.
I will just select United States and the configuration of the keyboard.
You can also choose whatever you like right here.
I'm going to go with American English and click on Next.
And this installation process will actually take about an hour to finish.
So, of course, this is not going to be an hour long video.
So I'm just going to skip through some longer parts of installation and I'm just going to cover the
steps where we actually have to choose something.
I will fast forward the installation so you don't have to sit through a one hour video.
OK, so let's wait for the next step.
And here is the next thing that comes up, which is configuring the network, so it asks us, please
enter the hostname for the system, you can type here.
Also anything that you want.
I'm just going to type here, Kelly, because we're installing Linux press enter and the next thing
that it asks is the domain name here.
For the purposes of the course, we don't need to set anything.
We can just leave it empty and we can press enter to continue.
Now, a user account must be created, so here you create the full name for the user for the purposes
of discourse.
I'm just going to call it Mr. Hacker.
Click on continue and username for the account that you will use to login to clinics.
The account name will also be Mr. Hacker.
For me, for you.
Choose anything that you like.
Just make sure that you remember it after the installation and press enter.
And now we need to set the password for the user here.
You type the password, whatever you like.
And here you confirm the password, once you do that, you also have an option to show password in clear.
I don't really need that.
So I'm just going to go on continue.
And you can see sometimes mouse actually works, but sometimes it doesn't.
So I'm just going to go and navigate again with my keyboard and select the time zone that I'm at.
Since I'm at Eastern Time Zone, I'm going to select Eastern.
You select whichever you want and it will continue with the installation.
Let's wait for the next step.
And here it is, partitioning this now, this might be a little bit harder for you to understand in
case your first time running Linux.
Nonetheless, here we want to go with the guided use entire disk.
We don't want to go any other option.
And here we want to select our own hard disk that we created.
So you will probably have only one option here.
Just select that one and click enter.
And this part, we want to go with all files in one partition, as it says it's recommended for new
users, for those of you that friendliness before you might also be familiar with slash home, slash
VA slash top.
And these are just some directories that we get inside of Linux.
Picture them as just some already made folders the clinic system gives us after the installation.
We don't want to separate any of these.
Let's pretend that we don't know anything about this.
So we're just going to go with the recommended settings that says all files in one partition and click
enter.
It will ask, has finished petitioning and write changes to this, we want to click, enter, and here
it asks us for the confirmation where we want to click.
Yes, so change from now.
Yes.
And click.
Enter.
And this will pretty much start the installation process of your clinics now, there will be a couple
of more questions during the installation.
So I'm just going to fast forward to the next question.
OK, so after a couple of minutes, we get this window prompted.
So it asks us to customize our own desktop with different settings.
So here, what we want to do is we want to select all of these that are checked by default, which is
desktop environment, X, F.C. and collection of tools.
However, we also want to check this large option right here.
This means that it will also install some additional tools inside of our Callinan's machine.
And the more tools, the better.
We never know when we are going to use some of these tools.
So let's just go and select large and we can proceed with the installation.
This next part will take some time to finish.
It will take around 30 to 40 minutes to finish.
So just sit back, grab something to drink, and I will see you guys when the next question pops up.
OK, so here's the next question, and this isn't really that important to us, it would be more important
if we were to install Linux as a main operating system and not as a virtual machine.
But let's read it nonetheless.
As it says, it seems that this is the new installation is the only operating system on this computer.
If so, it should be safe to install the bootloader to your primary drive warning if your computer has
another operating system that the installer failed to detect.
This will make that operating system temporarily unsuitable, though Grupp can be manually configured
later.
To put it now here we want to select.
Yes, because our virtual machine doesn't have any other operating system running besides Carol Linux.
So let's select.
Yes, right here and let's click on CONTINUE.
Under here, we want to select this as the age and we want to continue and this will pretty much finish
our installation, it will take a couple more minutes for this to end, and then we will have a working
clinic's virtual machine.
And here is the last question.
It says installation is complete, so it is time to put into your new system, make sure to remove any
installation media so that you put into the new system rather than restarting the installation.
Since we don't have any installation media, we can just click on continue without unplugging anything
or removing anything.
And our installation is complete now.
Our virtual machine will reboot and we will be able to use our Linux virtual machine.
Let's wait for a couple of seconds for our login screen to pop out.
And here is our login screen, our Caledonius machine is working perfectly us.
Now here we want to type in the username that we created during the installation, as well as the password
that was set during the installation.
So I'm just going to go with Mr. Hacker because that is what they set.
And I will type here the password for Mr. Hacker account.
This will open our desktop environment.
In case you're also stuck like this with a smaller screen, in order to make your machine full screen,
you can just lower the screen and enlarge it once again.
And this will actually fix the issue in 90 percent of cases.
And now we can see the clinic's desktop environment.
As I mentioned, and as we already know by now, this is a Linux system, so if you're not familiar
with the limbic system and Linux terminal command lines and commands that we will use, make sure you
check out the bonus section of the course where we actually cover Linux basics, where we teach the
basic commands, where we teach how we can use Linux terminal in order to execute what we want.
Nonetheless, if you are familiar with Linux and with Linux terminal, feel free to proceed with the
course.
We made our virtual hacking machine and the next thing that we want to do is we want to create a virtual
machine that we will use to attack.
OK, awesome.
We finished a big part of setting up our virtual lab and I will see you guys in the next video.