OK, let's think for setting up our environment is creating the tri hack me account, as I already mentioned
on this website, we have a couple of free practice examples that we can use to elevate our skills and
to learn even more about website vulnerabilities.
But for the start, we only want to create an account and later on we will use it throughout the course.
For now, let's just create it.
So this would be a rather short video.
All they want to do is you want to navigate to try hack me dot com.
It will open up this page where you want to go on joining now, since you don't have an account, you
want to set it up right here.
So it requires an username, email, password, experience level, and to select that, you're not a
robot, hopefully.
Now, make sure that you use a valid email, because it will ask you for verification after creating
an account, once you do that, you can log into your account, and I will do that right now.
And once you log in, you should have something like this now, after you verify your email, you can
go and browse to learn to compete and you can check out all of the modules that this website has so
we can go under the modules which we went to by going online.
And we have some Linux fundamentals, networking fundamentals, Web hacking fundamentals, which is
the module that we are interested in for this course.
But you also have some other modules that might interest you after four.
Now we're mostly focused on Web hacking.
So you want to go to that module and here we have a couple of free exercises.
Now, these are the exercises that we are going to touch inside of the course.
This is what the platform offers us for free.
And we're only going to use what the platform offers us for free.
And later on, if you decide that you like this platform, you can upgrade to premium.
But for this course, it will not be needed under the dashboard.
You have some other things, such as how many users there are, what rank you have, and rank is simply
just based on how many points you get by.
Solving different challenges in different rooms and room is something that other people create to make
practice examples on a hosted vulnerable machines.
Once you solve them, you get points.
Once you get points, you become a higher rank.
So this is just the basic things about the platform.
For now, it's just important that you have an account and later on we're going to join a room and start
exploring different vulnerabilities at different rooms.
Offer us if you created everything successfully.
We are fully done with setting up our environment and in the next section we can start off with website
and numeration and information gathering.
So there.