OK, just quick break, we have finished creating our environment and we are now ready to start getting
into all the website hacking and bug hunting, but there are a couple prerequisites that you might need
to do first.
In case you're a complete beginner and now is the best time to do them.
However, if you do feel confident knowing the basics of these things, feel free to continue with the
next section where we start a website and numeration and information gathering, and after that we dive
straight into website penetration testing and bug hunting.
However, as I mentioned, we need to be aware of bonus requirements first and lectures about them will
be inside the bonus sections, which are some very basic website development or website structure knowledge.
We must know what the email is, what JavaScript is, and other languages used in Web development.
We must know what they are for and how we can recognize them.
Besides that, we must also be familiar with Linux a little bit.
We must know the basic commands of Linux terminal and get familiarized with Linux structure itself.
And the last thing is that we must know networking a little bit as well, nothing to advance, but we
must know some basic things regarding IP addresses, local networks, DNS, HTP and so on and so on.
All three of these topics we have in the course added as bonus sections, the web development videos
and the links videos are in video format, while networking theory we offer in pedia format available
to download.
After you learn and get all three of them done and you feel comfortable with them, then we can proceed
to website penetration testing lectures.
OK, I just want to mention this and nonetheless we continue our journey in the next section where we
will learn how to enumerate websites and gather as much information about them as we can.